秦风同学 你为什么要报考刑警学院
Qin Feng,why do you want to get into the Criminal Police College?
这个问题很难回答吗
Is it so hard to answer?
一次考不上就考两次 没什么大不了
You can try again next year.It's no big deal.
给你买了机票 去泰国玩一周
I bought you the plane ticket for a one-week vacation in Thailand.
他会接待你
He will receive you.
他可是我表姐 你姑姥姥的老公堂弟的媳妇家的亲侄子
He is your great-aunt's husband's cousin's wife's nephew.
你远房表舅 大名鼎鼎的唐人街第一神探 唐仁
A distant uncle. The number one detective of Chinatown, Tang Ren.
时光一逝永不回
Time is gone with the wind.
往事只能回味
The past is past.
忆童年时竹马青梅
We are childhood sweetheart...
什么 王婆的儿子丢啦
What? Grandma Wang's son has gone missing?
这么大的案子 当然要接了
It's such an important case.I'll totally take it.
下车
Get out of the car.
没有找到黄金 查清了没有
The gold is not here.- Are you sure?
所有地方都找遍了 没有
We have searched everywhere.No sign of it.
黄SIR 坤泰来了
Sir, Kon Tai is here.
谢谢 黄SIR 谢什么
Thank you, Huang.- What for?
谢谢你帮我保护现场啊
For protecting the crime scene for me.
你是不是嗑药啦
Are you on drugs?
这是我的辖区 案子当然是我的了
This is my precinct,so the case is mine.
黄金案我查了三个月 眼看人赃并获
I have been on it for 3 months and almost solved it.
现在黄金没了 人也死了
Now the gold is gone,and the suspect is dead.
你说是你的案子啊 谁的地盘案子就是谁的
And you tell me this is your case?- My precinct, my case.
你再说一遍 我说了怎么啦
Come again?- You've got a problem with that?
信不信我揍你啊 我告你袭警 你信不信
Don't make me punch you!- I'll sue you for that.
我就袭你怎么啦 我就
You've got a problem with that?
疑似凶器
Suspected murder weapon.
愣着干什么 去看看有没有指纹啊
Check for finger prints.- Check for finger prints.
看看有没有其它的入口 窗户 暗道
Check for other entrances.- Check for other entrances.
去看看有没有其它的入口 窗户 暗道
把外面的监控都给我调出来 放到我的办公室
Pull the security footages outside the house and send to my office.
你再学我说话试试看 你学我说话试试看啊
Don't you repeat my words again!- Don't you repeat my words again!
胡啦 唐仁 走狗屎运了
I win! - Tang Ren, some dumb luck.
有事啊 不准赢了就跑
You have somewhere else to go?- Don't leave right after you win.
跑 我左有青龙饮水
Leave? I have an azure dragon drinking on the left...
右有白虎甩尾
...and a white tiger tail-whipping on the right.
兜里藏砂 财富到家
Put sand in your pocket and the money follows.
背后有树 财神光顾
Sit in front of a tree and God of Wealth will come.
我还要杀你们个 片甲不留 一丝不挂呀
I'm going to win everything on you including all your clothes.
你就算啦
Not you.
尸检报告
Autopsy report.
它是我的
It's mine!
看什么
What are you looking at?
干什么呢 你们
What are you doing here?
黑帮片啊 你们
You think you are in a gangster movie?
你们两个 到会议室来
You two,come to the conference room.
来啊 来啊
Come on.- Come on.
死者颂帕 男 三十七岁 颂帕工坊老板
The victim Sompat, 37-year-old male, owner of Sompat Workshop.
唐人街黄金失窃案嫌疑人
The suspect of the gold robbery in Chinatown.
死因为重物击打头部
The cause of death is blunt head trauma.
脑后致命伤口多达十一处
Eleven fatal wounds on the back of head.
按创源深度推断 凶手为中青年男性
According to the wound edges,the murderer is a mid-aged male.
凶器为 这把铁质降魔杵
The murder weapon is this iron vajra.
居然拿这个杀人
I can't believe he killed him with this.
指纹呢 正在采集
What about the finger prints?- We are processing it.
是 现场入口
Yes.- The entrance?
经过勘察 除了正门之外 其他地方不具备进入的条件
No other access to the workshop other than the front door.
是 是 是 密室杀人
Yes, yes, yes.- Locked room murder.
我已经把颂帕工坊 所有的监控录像都调出来了
I have pulled all the videofootages near Sompat Workshop.
能够看到入口的总共有四处
There are four cameras outside the front door.
一周内 内容自动覆盖
The footages are automatically overwritten every seven days.
我把素材已经带回来了 是
We have the footages.- Yes.
那些黄金呢 黄金不见了
What about the gold?- It's gone.
据我的推测应该是颂帕的同伙 杀人越货
I assume that Sompat's partners killed him and took the gold.
是
Yes.
你们都知道黄金是闫先生的
You all know that Mr. Yan owns the gold.
市长都给我打电话了 我压力很大的
Even the mayor called me for this.I feel a lot of pressure.
你们谁能抓住凶手 找回黄金
The one who nabs the suspect and gets the gold back...
谁就是 副局长
...will be the deputy chief.
YES SIR
Yes, sir.
唐仁 你的风水局不灵了 没道理啊
Tang Ren, you have lost your mojo.- It doesn't make sense.
来 来 来
Come on.
喂 唐哥 你什么时候过来呀
Hello!- Tang, when will you be here?
秦风
Qin Feng.
欢迎来泰国 不好意思 让你久等了
Welcome to Thailand.Sorry to keep you waiting.
你知道我是大侦探嘛 很忙 很多案子要办啦
You know I'm a famous detective,and have a lot on my plate.
我刚刚就是在办一个大案子啦
I was on a big case just now.
你是 哑巴吗 我...
Are you a mute?- I am...
不是哑巴 是结巴
Not a mute, but a stutterer.
考不上大学没关系啊 来泰国哈皮几天
Forget about the college. After a few happy days in Thailand...
保证连你婆婆都会忘记
...you will even forget your grandma.
曼谷可是全世界 最最好玩的地方
Bangkok is the most interesting place in the whole world...
男人的天堂啦
...and the paradise for guys.
泰哥 迟到要罚酒啊 有案子啦
Tai, you're late.- I was on a case.
怎么啦 不提啦
What's going on?- Nothing.
你亲戚呢 这里啊 这个就是啊
Where is your relative?- There he is.
不太像 没我帅 是吧
He doesn't look like you.- Not as cute as me, right?
这是我老大啦 唐人街警司 泰哥啦
He is my boss.Tai from the Chinatown Police.
放开玩 今天都算你泰哥的
Just have fun. It's all on me.
放心玩 我不会告诉你婆婆啦
Don't worry.I won't tell your grandma.
你多大啦 不会还是个雏吧
How old are you?Are you still a virgin?
你喜欢男的 人妖
You are into men? Transsexuals?
国内生活太紧绷了
He has been stressed out at home.
来 喝酒 喝酒 喝酒 未来七天交给表舅
Drink! You can count on me for the next few days.
一定让你终身难忘啦
I'll make it a life-enhancing trip for you.
干杯
Cheers!
干杯 你现在在曼谷
Cheers! You are in Bangkok.
你那杯也
Yours is laced too?
你喝了我那杯 那杯料更猛啦
You drank mine?Mine is even spicier!
嘘
Quiet!
你年纪轻轻不学好 怎么能学这种东西呢
How can you do something like this at such a young age?
我没... 没什么 没看够是吗
I didn't...- What? You didn't have enough?
告诉你 这次人家泼的是热水
You know,it is hot water this time.
下次可就是硫酸啦
It will be sulfuric acid next time.
你谁啊 我...我是他表...
Who are you?- I'm his...
他是我表弟啦 知道这位美丽
Cousin. He is my cousin brother.Do you know who is this...
高贵又善良的人是谁吗 还被你无耻的偷看
...noble and kind girl peeped by you?
她就是我的女房东啦
She is my landlady.
唐人街第一大美女 阿香
The most beautiful girl in Chinatown, Xiang.
这是你表弟 和我一样帅 对不对
He is your cousin?- As cute as me, right?
一样好色
No, as horny as you.
唐仁 来约牌呀
Tang Ren, play Mahjong with us.
一周后再说啦 没档期了
You have to wait for another week.I'm completely booked.
没档期了 这是谁呀
Uncle Xiang, morning.- Who is he?
我表弟啦
My cousin.
春春 又大了哦
Chun, they've grown bigger.
讨厌 有空过来喝茶
Nasty boy.Come around for tea sometime.
记住 以后千万别叫我表舅啊
Remember.Don't you ever call me uncle.
为什么 哪那么多为什么
Why?- Stop asking me why.
这里的人都以为我是九零后啦 那我叫你什么
They think I'm born in the 90s.- So what should I call you?
叫我小唐啊 你叫我呢
Call me Tang.- And what do you call me?
老秦 我帮你安排好了这一周的行程啦
Qin. I have made you a schedule for the week.
湄南河 大市场 人妖表演 郑王庙
Menam River, floating market,transsexual show, Wat Arun.
明天我先带你去 泰国最出名的 大皇宫
We'll visit the most scenic spot in Thailand, the Grand Palace.
我想看暹罗连体人 什么东西
I want to see the Siamese Twin.- What?
埃勒里・奎因 侦探小说
Ellery Queen.The detective fiction.
我听你婆婆说 你经常喜欢那些
Your grandma told me that you are into...
乱七八糟的东西 不是乱...
...all the freaky stuff.- Not freaky.
小说和电影都是唬你们这些小孩子啦
The novels and movie are to fool kids like you.
你要喜欢侦探 马上陪我去办个失踪案
If you want to be a detective,let's solve a missing person case.
要搞成这样吗 一模一样
Do you want it like this?- Exactly like this.
借点钱啦 很快就还你啊
Lend me some money.I'll pay you back soon.
SURPRISE
Surprise!
王婆 你的儿子找到啦
Grandma Wang, I found your son.
斑斑
Ban Ban.
怎么变样了 瘦脱相了嘛
Why does it look different?- It has been starving.
你喂两天就好啦
It will recover in a couple of days.
怎么不认识妈妈了
It doesn't recognise me.
认识了 认识了 认识了吧 你看
He does now. See?
谢谢
Thanks.
王婆 我要去办大案子 我要先走啦
Grandma Wang, I'm on a big case.I have to go now.
表...
Un...
小唐 你这属于诈骗 你懂个屁
Tang, this is fraud.- What do you know?
我这叫关心老年人心理健康
I care about the mental health of elderly people.
你管它黑狗白狗 能让老人家开心就是好狗啦
As long as the dog makes her happy.
好借好还 再借不难啦
Here you are.
这就是你说的案
This is your so-called case?
急你个头啊 我现在就带你去办大案啦
Be patient. I'll take you to solve a crime now.
这个啦
This one.
怎么样啊 好...
What do you think?- So...
好看吧 好丑
So pretty?- So ugly.
小孩子懂个屁
What do you know?
强叔 给打个折吧 给你算六折
Qiang, give me some discount.- Forty percent.
再借一次啦 什么
Lend me some more.- What?
好借好还 再借不难啦
I'll pay you back soon.
你不是说带我 带...
I thought you were going to take me...
这就是破案用的啦 快点啦 快点 快点啦
It's for the case.Come on, come on.
干什么 人不大 脾气还不小
What are you doing?Why are you being so grumpy?
你去哪里啊
Where are you going?
我最恨骗子 我怎么骗你啦
I hate liars.- How did I lie to you?
你是侦探 如假包换
You are a detective?- Absolutely.
买链子是为了破案
You bought the necklace to solve a case?
当然啦
Of course
不是为了给你那女房东过生日
It's not a birthday gift for your landlady?
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
接我迟到 打牌去了吧
You were late to pick me up because you were playing mahjong.
你又知道
How did you know that?
你那天身上烟味很重 眼睛里都是血丝
Strong smell of cigarettes,bloodshot eyes...
指甲里都是泥垢 尤其是右手
...and dirt in your fingernails,especially your right hand.
左手被烟熏黄 但你平时用右手抽烟
Your left hand was stained,but you are a right-handed smoker.
裤子右腿比左腿脏 裤腿被磨得发亮
Your right trouser leg was dirtier and they were both worn out.
这些特征组合在一起 只能产生一个行为 打麻将
All these signs lead to one thing,playing mahjong.
胡啦
I win!
小说里学的 是不是
You learn that from the novels?- Am I right?
那天我... 我平时还是有很多案子的啦
I usually have a lot of cases.
比如 调查失踪人口啊
For example?- Search for missing persons.
找猫狗 跟踪嫌疑犯啦
Cats and dogs.- Tail a suspect.
抓小三 押送重要物资啦
Someone's mistress.- Escort important supplies.
送快递 你都知道
Express delivery.- How did you know it all?
都是中文的 呢实在是太LOW了
They are all in Chinese.You are such a loser.
你还能去哪里呀 反正还剩下六天
Where else can you go?It's just six more days.
你看我不开心 就少看 我再陪你玩六天
If I upset you, you can look away.I'll be with you for six days.
也算是能交差啦
Then my job is done.
明天就陪你去大皇宫
I'll take you to the Grand Palace tomorrow.
那你不准在骗我 我最恨别人撒谎
Don't lie to me again.I hate liars.
行 行 行 不骗 不骗 不骗
Fine. No more lies.
指纹对比结果出来了 就是他
We've received the results for the finger prints. It's him.
出发 抓人
Let's go. Get him.
没错 说的就是你 铁血神探
Yeah. I'm talking about you.Hot Fuzz.
GO GO GO
Go, go, go!
你说阿香 见了这个会不会亲亲我呀
Do you think Xiang will kiss me when she sees this?
你也试一试呀 刮完帅得很啦
You should try it, too.You will get cuter.
你是不是 觉得我很差劲啊
You think I am a loser,don't you?
你觉得你比我聪明吗 那好
You think you are smarter than me?Fine.
咱俩玩个游戏 互相给对方提问
Let's play a game. Quiz.
我答不出给你五十铢 你答不出给我一百铢
If I lose, I'll give you 50 baht.If you lose, give me 100 baht.
怎么样
How about that?
你比我聪明嘛 好
Because you are smarter than me.- All right.
你小孩子 你先问
You are younger, you first.
地球到太阳的直线距离
What is the linear distance between the earth and sun?
平均值一万四千九百六十万千米
The mean distance is 149,600,000 kilometers.
他叫什么名字啊
What is his name?
叫什么 我也不知道啦
So what's the answer?- I don't know, either.
可乐 冰的
Buy me a coke. Cold one.
别气啦 你看你眉心发红
Don't be upset.It's reddish between your eyes.
马上要走桃花运啦
It means you are getting lucky with the ladies.
你印堂发黑
It's blackish at the top of your nose bridge.
你要倒大霉 呸 呸 呸
You'll be in big trouble.- Touch wood!
你好 你杀了人
Hello.- You killed someone and...
警察正要抓你 好笑吗
...the police is after you.- You think that's funny?
警察已经包围你了
You are surrounded by the cops.
听着 证据确凿
Listen.The evidence is conclusive.
抓到你就死定了 想活命 快跑
You are a dead man if you get arrested. Run for your life.
准备
Ready.
GO
Go!
追 追 追
Come on, hurry up! Hurry up!
他是警察 走啊
He is a cop. Run!
别管我 追啊
Let me be. Get him!Get him!
不是说去大皇宫吗
I thought you were taking me to the Grand Palace.
对啊 去大皇宫啊
Yes, to the Grand Palace.
警 警 警 警察为什么抓你啊 对啊 为什么
Why..Why is the police after you?- Yes, why?
我问你呢
I'm asking you.
为什么
Why?
你打我 我没打你
You hit me?- No, I didn't.
你没打我吗 没啊
You didn't hit me?- No.
为...为什么抓你啊
Why are they after you?
他们说我杀人啦 你杀了谁呀
They said I killed someone.- Who did you kill?
我杀了谁呀 你说你杀了谁呀
Who did I kill?- Tell me who you killed.
你说我杀了谁呀 我怎么知道你杀了谁呀
- Tell me who I killed.- How would I know?
我怎么知道我杀了谁啊
How would I know?
黄兰登你什么意思
Huang Landeng, how can you do something like this?
你不打声招呼就到我的地盘上抓人 还抓我的人 混蛋
You catch my man in my precinct without my knowledge?
你的人 废话
Your man?- Of course.
整个唐人街谁不知道唐仁是我的马仔啊
Everyone in Chinatown knows that Tang Ren is my man.
你问问他们哪一个不知道
You can ask them about it.
你有什么证据抓人 兰登 证据
What's your evidence?- Landeng, the evidence.
三个月前唐人街 四家金行 在一夜之间发生盗窃
Three months ago in Chinatown,four gold shops were burgled.
丢失金条金块一百零一公斤
101 kg of gold has gone missing.
我们最先锁定的盗窃团伙中的一个就是
The first suspect we lock in the robbery gang...
颂帕工坊中的手工匠人 颂帕
...is the craftsman Sompat from Sompat Workshop.
而且我们最后确认 失窃的黄金也藏在他的工坊之中
We have verified that the stolen gold is in his workshop.
四月十五号 我们准备去抓颂帕的时候
On April 15th, when we were about to arrest Sompat...
发现他已经被人杀了
...he was found dead.
死亡的时间是 四月十四日晚上十一点到一点钟
The time of death is from 11 pm to 1 am on April 14th.
我们多次排查
According to our thorough investigation...
能够进入工坊的入口只有一个
...there is only one entrance to his workshop...
那就是工坊正门
...that is the front door.
工坊正门外面有四个监视器
There are four cameras outside the front door.
我们最后排查之后发现 在案发时间内
We found that during the time the murder happened...
唯一进入过现场的人
...the only one who went into the crime scene...
唐仁
...was Tang Ren.
凶器上全都是唐仁的指纹
Tang Ren's finger prints are all over the murder weapon...
而且黄金不翼而飞
...and the gold is gone.
所以我们最后可以断定
So we figure out that...
唐仁 就是五个嫌犯中的小个子
...Tang Ren is the short guy among the five suspects.
他杀害同伴 黑吃黑 谋财害命
He double-crossed his partner and killed him for the gold.
只要我们找到唐仁 就可以找回失窃的黄金
As long as we find Tang Ren,we can retrieve the stolen gold.
成功了没有 成功了
Are we clear?- Yes!
坤SIR 还有什么话要说
Kon, do you still have something to say?
不是这里我要声明一下 我跟这个唐仁是没有任何关系的
First of all, I have nothing to do with that Tang Ren.
不是你说整个唐人街的人都知道
I thought you said everyone in Chinatown knows that...
唐仁是你的马仔吗 而且听说那个私人侦探社
...Tang Ren is your man.I heard you are the big boss...
你就是幕后的老板
...of that private detective agency.
我警告你不要乱讲话啊 我告你诽谤 你知道吗
Don't you say anything like that.I'll sue you for slander.
我告你诽谤啊
I'll sue you for slander.
他诽谤我呀
He is slandering me.
他在诽谤我呀
你好 泰哥 你
Hello.- Tai, you...
你什么你呀 你竟然敢杀人呐你
Cut it out.How dare you murder a man?
我限你六小时之内 来警局自首
I give you six hours to turn yourself in.
泰哥 我 我什么我
Tai, I...- Cut it out.
你千万不要想着跑路啊
Don't run away from this!
你千万不要想着坐走私船离开泰国
Never take a smuggler to leave Thailand...
再转到越南 缅甸 老挝 柬埔寨
...and transfer to Laos,Cambodia, Vietnam and Burma.
不要让我见到你 你让我见到你 我分分钟弄死你啊
Never let me see you again!I will eat you alive if I do.
我与罪恶不共戴天
I will not live under the same sky with crimes.
好
Great!
现在怎么办
What should we do now?
我一定要找坤泰问个清楚啊
I have to see Kon Tai and find out what it's about.
你自首吧 什么
You should turn yourself in.- What?
自首吧 反正泰国没死刑
Turn yourself in. There is no death sentence in Thailand.
你随便坐四十几年牢就出来了
You only have to serve a sentence of about 40 years.
听听 听听你说的是人话吗
Are you listening to yourself?
随便坐四十几年牢
Who wants to be in jail for 40 years?
我可是你舅舅 亲舅舅啊 表的
I am your uncle.- A distant uncle.
血浓于水呀 谁让你杀人了
Blood is thicker than water.- But you are a murderer.
我没杀人啊 你去跟警察说
I am not.- Tell this to the police.
我说他们会听我的吗
Will they listen to me?
本来就没有身份 不犯事还好
I'm not a citizen here.It's all right when I behave.
犯了事 还不是他们说我什么就是什么吗
But once I break the law, they can do whatever they want to me.
我可不想一辈子坐牢啦
I don't want to spend the rest of my life in prison.
坐牢也跟我没关系
It's none of my business.
反正我是不跑了
I don't want to run anymore.
你刚刚袭警了 知道吗
You assaulted the police.
在泰国袭警罪是很大的
It's a felony in Thailand.
至少关你十几年牢啦
You have to stay in jail for at least a dozen of years.
我不知情
I didn't know anything.
你人在泰国 谁管你呀
You are in Thailand now.It's not up to you anymore.
你连中国话都说不利落 谁听你的
You can't speak fluent Mandarin,who would listen to you?
抓住你 先暴打一顿 然后不管你三七二十一 往牢里一扔
They would beat you up and throw you in prison.
你知道泰国什么最多
Do you know what they have most in Thailand?
就你这姿色 进去没别的
For a cute guy like you,when you get in jail...
先被十几个大汉 随便轮奸几十遍啦
...you will be gang-raped by a dozen of big guys.
南派莫家拳 承让
Mohist Fist of South Sect!Thank you.
承让 承让什么呀承让
Thank you? Cut it out.
给我套上
Blindfold him.
狗日的 你戳我的眼
You scum! You poked my eyes...
你还掏 掏我的裆 行了
...and grabbed my private area.- Enough.
东西呢 什么
Where is it?- What?
还跟我装 是吗 你想要什么我都给你呀
You are still playing dumb?- I'll give whatever you want.
看来我暗示的还不够明显 我问你金子呢
It seems you didn't take the hint.Where is the gold?
金子在他脖子上呢 脖子
The gold is on his neck.- Neck?
还蛮横的嘛 都是道上的
You look like a tough man.- We are all street boys.
给点面子啦 为什么不完整
Show me some respect.- Why is it incomplete?
纹一半太疼 受不了 就喊停了
I couldn't stand the pain,so I told them to stop.
还纹条残龙 别
A half-baked dragon.- Don't!
别什么别 我问的不是这条破链子
Cut it out!It's not the gold I want.
我问你 你把颂帕弄死以后 黄金运哪去了
After you killed Sompat,where did you take the gold?
颂帕是谁啊 你拿人家东西
Who is Sompat?- You took their stuff.
你就还给人家 闭嘴 我可是你舅舅啊
Just give it back.- Shut up! I am your uncle here.
原来是舅舅啊
Turns out you are his uncle.
不说 我就打死他
Tell us or I'll shoot him.
打死他 我也不知道啊
That won't make me know something I don't.
你快告诉他 我可是你外甥啊
Just tell him. I am your nephew.
表的
No, just a distant nephew.
我 血浓于水啊
Don't.- Blood is thicker than water.
给点提示呗 那一箱金子
Give me a hint.- That box of gold.
你说 那个雕塑作坊 往下说
You mean in the statue workshop?- Go on.
那人打电话 让我去接箱子
That man called me and asked me to pick up the box.
我不知道里面是金子啊
I didn't know there was gold inside.
你把箱子放哪了 那人 让我送到
Where did you take the box?- That man asked me to...
海天大厦地下停车场
...deliver it to the underground parking lot of Haitian Mansion...
一辆面包车的旁边啦
...and drop it off next to a van.
金刚 看好他们两个 好
King Kong, watch over them.- Okay.
越南仔 咱俩找箱子去 走
Vietnamese, let's go find the box.- Okay.
如果你敢骗我 弄死我
If you lie to me...- You can kill me.
你吃什么
You want to eat?
偷我们的黄金 害得我们就吃这
You stole our gold,so we have to eat this.
砸呀
Do it!
又来呀 你松手 你松手 松手 松手啊
What are you doing?Let go, let go! Let go!
一起松啊 好
We let go together.- Fine.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
链子给我啊 给 给 给
Give me the necklace.- Here.
快点 快跑啊
Come on. Run!
松手 松手 松手
Let go, let go, let go!
都怪你 大皇宫呢
It's all your fault.What about the Grand Palace?
你一来泰国就这么多事
You have caused me so much trouble.
我还没说你是丧门星呢
You are such a bird of ill omen.
现在去哪啊 我得把这个给阿香送去啊
Where are you going now?- I have to give this to Xiang.
你疯啦 顺便让泰哥 和我们在那里碰个头
Are you out of your mind?- I'll ask Tai to meet us there.
我可不想死的糊里糊涂的啦
I don't want to die for no good reason.
那几个匪徒 怎么会知道我们在哪
How did the gangsters know where we were?
什么意思啊 匪徒身上会有手铐
What are you talking about?- How did they get the handcuffs?
你是说 警察里面有他们的内线
You mean there is a mole in the police?
那也不可能是泰哥啦
Even so, it can't be Tai.
你信他吗 他肯定不会骗我啦
You trust him?- I'm sure he won't lie to me.
你猜 这车子能动吗
Do you think the bike is still working?
废话真多 管他要份案情报告
Cut the crap.Ask him for the case report.
中文的 干什么
In Chinese.- Why?
你不想知道你杀了谁吗
Don't you want to know who you killed?
快进来 快点
Come in. Hurry up!
你们怎么来了 整个曼谷都在通缉你们
What are you doing here? You are wanted in the whole Bangkok.
生日快乐 神经病
Happy birthday.- You're crazy.
我没杀人你信吗
I didn't kill anyone.Do you believe me?
我信你没有用 要警察信你才行啊
So what if I believe you? You have to make the police believe you.
所以我才约泰哥来这里问个清楚啊
So I want to meet Tai here to find out.
那金子到底是不是你们偷的 我
Did you steal the gold or not?- I...
是泰哥
Is it Tai?
快上去
Go upstairs.
你们找谁
What do you want?
你是阿香吧 我们是唐仁的朋友
You are Xiang, right?We are friends of Tang Ren.
唐仁是谁 别装了
Who is Tang Ren?- Drop the act.
他不最爱你吗 你们到底谁啊
Aren't you the love of his life?- Who the heck are you?
我们是 唐仁的 同伙
We are Tang Ren's partners.
快进来 快点
Come in. Hurry up!
你们真的偷金子了 他没分给你吗
Did you really steal the gold?- Didn't he share it with you?
分了呀
Yes.
漂亮吧
Isn't it pretty?
他也太抠了吧 就给你这么一点
He is so cheap. You deserve more.
到底偷了多少 新闻上没说啊
They didn't say how much you stole in the news.
他在哪呢 我让他亲自跟你说
Where is he?I'll ask him to tell you himself.
非逼我见面
Why does he have to meet me here?
这要是被别人看见了 我这警察还做不做了
If anybody sees this,I will be fired.
人呢
Where is he?
黄SIR
Huang.
快上去
Go upstairs.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY 谢谢
Happy birthday.- Thank you.
嘘
Quiet!
你一个人在家 对啊
Are you home alone?- Yes.
没有人陪你过生日啊
Nobody is celebrating your birthday with you?
一大把年纪了过什么生日啊
I'm too old for that.
谁 没谁
Who was that?- No one.
不对
No way.
黄SIR 上面真的没人
Detective Huang,there is nobody up there.
黄SIR
Detective Huang.
这谁啊
Who is he?
我表哥 你不是说没人吗
My cousin.- You said there's nobody here.
他不是人
He is nobody.
傻的
He is retarded.
黄SIR 知道你忙 就不送你了
I won't see you out since you are so busy.
有机会来我们夜上海玩 就在隔壁的
Come to Night In Shanghai sometime. I'm right next door.
对了 你今天特别帅 拜拜
By the way, you are so handsome.Bye bye.
他们是谁呀 唐仁同伙
Who are they?- Tang Ren's partners.
什么同伙 偷金店的同伙
Partners for what?- The gold shop burglary.
他们不是我同伙啊 我们就是他同伙
They are not my partners.- We are.
金店真的是你偷的 金店不是我偷的
Did you really steal the gold?- No, I didn't.
我们一起偷的 你胡说
We did it together.- Nonsense!
那人也是你们杀的 人是他杀的
You killed the man, too?- He killed him.
不是我杀的 就是你杀的
No, I didn't.- Yes, you did.
人真的是你杀的 人真的不是我杀的
You really killed him?- No, I didn't.
金子也不是我偷的 我根本就没有同伙
And I didn't stole the gold.I don't have any partners.
那 我是谁 我知道你是谁啊
So, who am I?- I know who you are.
他知道你是谁啦 那他们到底是谁啊
He knows who you are.- But who the heck are they?
对啊 你们到底是谁呀
Yes. Who the heck are you?
成功了没有 没有
Is it done?- No.
跟我来
Come with me.
黄SIR 你怎么又来了
Detective Huang,what brings you here again?
那个 楼上只有我表哥
There is only my cousin upstairs.
真的没有别人了
Nobody else.
大变活人
He shows up out of thin air.
这是我另外一个表哥 二表哥
He is my other cousin.- Second cousin.
你到底有几个表哥
How many cousins do you have?
那刚才那个大表哥呢
Where is your eldest cousin?
三表哥
Your third cousin?
HI HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU
Happy Birthday to you.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU
SURPRISE HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU
Surprise!- Happy Birthday to you.
谢谢
Thank you, guys.
表妹 今天这个生日你一定会很惊喜
You must feel surprised today.
祝你幸福 谢谢 谢谢你们
Be happy.- Thank you, guys.
表哥还有事 我先走了
I have something else to do.I have to go.
二表哥 三表哥再见
Goodbye, cousins.
生日快乐 大表哥再见
Happy Birthday to you.- Goodbye, eldest cousin.
阿香啊你的口味真的太重了
Xiang, your taste of men is so special.
那个黄SIR 我送你吧
Detective Huang, I'll see you out.
泰哥 这是我最后一次帮你了
Tai.- This is the last time I help you.
你要的东西
I've got you the things you need.
船都帮你找好了 时间 地点都在里面
The time and place are all in here.
泰哥 什么都不要讲了
Tai.- Don't say anything.
我只能帮你到这里了
I can't help you anymore.I don't want to see you again...
最好这辈子都不要再见了 保重吧
...for the rest of my life.Take care.
泰哥
Tai.
这么多年感情 无以为报
I have nothing to repay you for all these years' of brotherhood.
传家宝送给你留个念想啦 什么鬼呀
Keep my heirloom as a token.- What the heck is this?
开过光 很灵的
It's been blessed and efficacious.
开车不用系安全带啦
With it, you can drive without fastening the seatbelt.
我还是系上点比较好啊
I'd better fasten it.
你真没杀人 当然 我真没有杀人啦
You really didn't kill that man?- Of course I didn't.
那你去那干嘛 我那天在打牌
So why did you go there?- I was playing mahjong...
接到一个陌生人的电话 你好
...and I got a phone callfrom a stranger.
电话那人 让我四月十四日晚十二点
The caller asked me to go to Sompat Workshop...
到颂帕工坊 拉尊佛像
...at 12pm on April 14th to pick up a Buddha statue...
送到海天大厦停车场
...and drop it off at the parking lot of Haitian Mansion.
还说 那个 会把酬劳给我
And he said he would pay me.
那人让我填了一张取货单
That man asked me to fill out a carrier's note...
然后就把钱给我啦
...and gave me the money.
我走时那人没死啊
The man was still alive when I left.
箱子呢
Where is the box?
按规定 送到海天大厦停车场
I delivered it to the parking lot of Haitian Mansion as asked.
那里只有一辆车在等啊
There was only one van waiting.
你没见着收货人 没有啊
Did you see the consignee?- No, I didn't.
那人直接让我把箱子放在车旁边
That man asked me to put the box next to the van.
那地方 前高后下
That place is higher at front and lower in the rear.
阴气太重啦 一看就是不祥之地嘛
It is so gloomy.I'm sure it's a jinx.
谁愿意久留呢 你没打开箱子看看啊
So I left right away.- Didn't you open the box?
那箱子是封死的嘛 谁知道里面是黄金呢
It was sealed. Who would have thought there was gold inside?
有意思 有意思
Interesting.- Interesting?
从证据看 你就是凶手
According to the evidence,you are the murderer.
我不是凶手啦
No, I am not.
那人怎么死的 我哪知道他怎么死的
So how did he die?- How would I know?
你不想知道真相是什么吗
Don't you want to know the truth?
我想活下去啦 别走
I want to survive.- Stay here.
不走干嘛 破案
Why should I stay?- Solve the case.
没发烧啊 这孩子怎么还说胡话了呢
You are not having a fever.Why do you talk nonsense?
多好玩啊 你别扯淡了
It's fun.- Nonsense!
那我的命在陪你玩 要玩你自己玩
I'm risking my life.You are on your own now.
我必须走
I have to leave.
船来啦 老子要闪人啦
The boat is here.I'm getting out of here.
再见THAILAND THAILAND
Goodbye, Thailand. Thailand.
我不知道 我回去 怎么向父老乡亲们交代
I don't know how to explain to the folks.
出来混得好好的 怎么突然就回去了呢
Why do I suddenly go back while I have a good life here?
我想想 这辈子再也见不到阿香
To think that I'll never see Xiang again...
我的心就像刀割一样疼 刀割一样你懂吗
...I am torn with grief.Torn with grief, you know?
快 快 快 马上走了
Come on, hurry up.We are leaving.
他们也去中国 谁说我们去中国
Are they going to China, too?- Who told you that?
那去哪里呀 赤道几内亚
So where are you going?- Equatorial Guinea.
什么 赤道几内亚
What?- Equatorial Guinea.
赤道几内亚是什么地方 非洲吧
Where is that?- I think it's in Africa.
我们会死在那里吗 也许 我们会 死船上
Will we die there?- Maybe we will die on the boat.
快上船 快点 NO NO NO
Get on board.- No, no, no.
你们到底走不走 不走啦
Are you coming or not?- No, we are not.
不走啦
We are not?
我宁可坐牢也不上这船啦 你们走吧
I'd rather go to prison.You go ahead.
走 开船
Go.
我们去把案子给破了吧 做梦吧
Let's solve the case.- No way.
你个警校都没考上的胎盘还破案
You are just a loser rejected by the police college.
你不是唐人街第一神探嘛
You are the Number One Detective of Chinatown, aren't you?
神探 神探个屁
Detective my foot.
我不是 你也不是
I'm not a detective,neither are you.
咱俩加一起 没准行
But we can probably solve it together.
你干嘛
What are you doing?
探案得需要装备啦
We need to equip ourselves for the case.
怎么一点儿侦探的样子都没有啊
Why don't we look like detectives at all?
这是什么
What's this?
近可测风水 远可断吉凶
It can check feng shui and find out good or bad luck.
古拿来探宝 我用来追凶
It was used to seek treasures.I use it to track down murderers.
五千年历史 中华之瑰宝
It's a Chinese treasure of five thousand years.
老美找外星人都用它啦
The Americans use it to find aliens.
英文名叫 弟我姓肉的
Its English name is Dowsing Rod.
我们老祖宗唤它 寻龙尺
And our ancestors called it Dragon-Seeking Ruler.
那车原来就停在那里 现在不见啦
The van was parked right there.But now it's gone.
你寻出什么了
What have you found?
心意合一 剑指为南
Due to the unity in the heart,it points to the south.
凶手在南方
The murderer is in the south.
无牌车 废弃停车场
A van without plate.An abandoned parking lot.
阴谋 这想想都是阴谋
Conspiracy.It must be a conspiracy.
车停在这儿很久了
The van had been parked here for a long time.
左前胎是新换的
The left-front tyre is new.
干什么 福尔摩斯能在地上
What are you doing?- Sherlock Holmes can identify...
闻出马车的种类
...the carriage type by the smell on the ground.
鱼腥味 闻到了吗
Fish odour. Do you smell that?
没有啊 完全没有啊
No. Not at all.
你狗鼻子啊
You have a dog's nose?
你那辆车还有什么别的特征
What else do you remember about that van?
没有啊 难道我们要在曼谷
Nothing. Do we have to find that seafood van...
六百万辆车里 找出那辆运海鲜的面包车
...among the six million vehicles in Bangkok?
曼谷的海鲜市场没几个吧
There aren't many seafood market in Bangkok, are there?
先去孔提 在南方
Let's go to Klong Toey first.It's in the south.
有啊 我们是有这样一辆白色面包车 不过一个月前就报废了
We had a white van like this,but it was scrapped a month ago.
报废了 那车在哪里 废车厂
Scrapped? So where is it now?- The junk yard.
什么 你们会给自己垃圾做登记吗
What? Do you register your own garbage at home?
你们要找自己去找
You have to find it yourselves.
走 快点啦
Come on, let's go.
快点啦
Come on.
气流四散 往而不复
The airflow scatters in all directions and doesn't come back.
这简直就是凶宅嘛 干什么要快点
It's a haunted house.Do what you have to do.
此地不宜久留啦
We can't stay here for too long.
你干嘛 懂什么叫专业吗
What are you doing?- This is called professional.
这里确实没有其它入口
There is really no other entrance here.
所以呢 你就是凶手
So?- So you are the murderer.
我走的时候他就坐在这里啦
He sat right here when I left.
但你走之后没人进来
But nobody else came here after you left.
所以呢 所以 你就是凶手
So?- So you are the murderer.
有什么没 什么都没有
You got anything?- Nothing.
你除了靠 还能不能说点别的
Can you say something else other than that?
房间整洁没异味
The room is neither messy nor smelly.
不是伪娘就是GAY
He must be a sissy or a gay.
这边都找过了 根本就没有
I have searched here and found nothing at all.
这不还有俩屋呢嘛 再仔细找找
There are two more rooms.Keep searching.
这一大堆金子 哪藏得住
You can't hide so much gold without being noticed.
肯定是让唐仁这小子带走了
Tang Ren must have moved it.
喂
Hello.
货还没有找到
We haven't found it.
肯定 被唐仁那小子带走了
It must have been moved by Tang Ren.
好 好 我马上就到
Okay. I will be right there.
走
Let's go!
戳我的眼 还掏我的裆
He poked my eyes and grabbed my private part.
我现在后面还火辣辣的痛 让我逮着他非弄死他
My behind is still burning now.- I'll kill him when I get him.
弄死他
That scum.- Kill him.
看什么呢 没什么
What are you looking at?- Nothing.
他们给谁打电话呢
Who was he calling?
那个最早给你打电话让你跑的人
The man who called you and told you to run away.
那个看见我们却放过我们的人
The man who saw us but let us go.
黄兰登的助手 他为什么这么做呢
Huang Landeng's assistant?Why would he do that?
你猜 他以为黄金在我身上
Give it a guess.- He thought I had the gold.
所以不想让警察抓到我啦
So he doesn't want me to be arrested.
你还不算太笨 难道他也是盗匪之一
You are not that dumb after all.- Is he one of the robbers?
加上死了那个 五个 齐了
Plus the victim.That's all five of them.
那是谁骗我把黄金运出去的呢
So who asked me to moved the gold?
找着那个人 杀人案就破了
If we find him,we can solve the case.
那我就清白啦 可他是谁呢
And I will be proven innocent.But who is he?
不知道 不知道
I don't know.- You don't know?
折腾了一晚上你跟我说不知道
You tell me you don't know after such a long night?
我要先看看监控内容
I have to watch the surveillance footages first.
那些东西都在警察局里啦 对呀
They are in the police office.- Yes.
对呀 所以呢
Yes.- So?
所以呢就看不到啦 必须看到
So you have no access to them.- I have to watch them.
你以为警察局是你家开的吗
You think you own the police office or what?
你说看就看
You can't do whatever you want.
天快亮了 我们去找泰哥帮忙
It's nearly dawn.We can ask Tai for help.
不睡会儿了吗 我们两天都没有睡觉啦
Don't you want to have some sleep?We haven't slept for two days.
把你抓进去 你能睡四十年
When you are put into jail,you can sleep for 40 years.
你好 泰哥 是我啊
Hello.- Tai, it's me.
唐仁啊 你到马来西亚还是韩国了
Tang Ren, are you calling from Malaysia or South Korea?
我在你家门口啊
I'm at your doorstep.
你们为什么不走呢 我也要证明我自己是清白的呀
Why are you still here?- I have to prove my innocence.
我们要破案 你以为这是拍电影吗
We have to solve the case.- You think you are in a movie?
你王者归来吗 你得要帮助我
The Return of the King?- You've got to help me.
我已经帮你跑路啦
I helped you leave Thailand.
你还得要帮助我啊 我再帮你我警察干不干了
You've got to help me again.- I will be fired.
他们要是知道你收黑钱 开小赌场
If they know you accepted bribes and owned a mini casino...
你居然敢威胁我 你老婆要知道你
How dare you threaten me?- If your wife finds out that...
包养小老婆 我该怎么帮你呢
...you have a mistress...- How can I help you?
我们要看颂帕的详细资料啊
We want the details on Sompat.
和他近半年的消费清单
And his expense lists for the last six months.
好 我们还要进警察局呀
Okay.- We have to enter the station.
看监控录像 你们疯了吗
To watch the video footages.- Are you crazy?
你连局长的老婆的都 我们计划一下啦
You and the chief's wife...- Let's draw up a plan.
黄兰登为了破案 把所有的电脑资料 都放在他的办公室里
Huang Landeng keeps all the computer data in his office.
而要去到他的办公室 必须要经过
To get to his office,you have to go through...
几十个警察 几十个警察的办公区
...the office areas of a dozen of cops.
根本不可能的嘛 那就晚上进去啦
It's impossible.- We can go in at night.
晚上所有电脑系统自动关闭
The computer system is turned off automatically at night.
我也没有密码啦
And I don't have the password.
就白天 就一会儿
We go there during daytime.It won't take too long.
你们两个都是被通缉的人
You are both wanted.
你以为警察都是瞎的吗
Do you think all the cops are blind?
看我干什么 你去把他们引走
Why are you looking at me?- You draw them away.
引走 什么叫我把他们 引走
Draw them away?What are you talking about?
加大警力到机场 火车站 码头
Send more people to the airport,railway station and ports...
把唐仁给我找出来
...to find Tang Ren.
如果唐仁离开曼谷 你们就都给我滚蛋 OUT
If Tang Ren leaves Bangkok,you will be fired. Out!
GET OUT
Get out!
一个小个子 满头卷发
A short guy with curly hair...
小眼睛 镶了一颗大金牙
...small eyes and a gold tooth.
奇怪了 找遍整个曼谷都找不到
Weird. We can't find him anywhere in Bangkok.
快
Hurry!
萨瓦迪卡
Hello!
唐仁 抓人啊
Tang Ren? Get him!
堵住他 快点
Get him! Hurry!
抓住他 快点
你给我下来 你给我下来
Get down!
砸死他
Throw!
别踩 我是局长
Don't step on me! I'm the chief.
到案发前一共七天
Seven days of video footages before the murder...
四个摄像头的所有视频资料都在这里了
...on the four cameras are all here.
从第一天开始 一起放给我看
Play them for me,starting from day 1 .
太多了 看不完了
It's impossible for you to watch them all.
快放
Just play them.
快进
Fast forward.
再快
Faster.
你这么快 你看得出什么呢
What can you see at such a high speed?
再快
Faster.
快
黄SIR 黄SIR 擦擦
Sir, let me help you.
擦个屁啊 抓人啊
Stop it! Get him!
看出什么来啦 我要的东西呢
What did you get?- Where is the stuff I want?
都在这里 都是泰文的
All in here. They are in Thai.
你在干嘛 我的电脑坏了
What are you doing here?- My computer crashed.
我借你的电脑打打游戏啦
So I use yours to play games.
打游戏
Play games?
这都被你发现了
Busted.
我看一看片片嘛
I was just watching some porns.
颂帕九年前妻子和他离了婚
Sompat got divorced with his wife nine years ago.
原因这没写
It doesn't mention the reason here.
从莱堪府搬来曼谷 一直开这个雕塑工坊
He moved to Bangkok from Lamkan and ran the statue workshop.
他有一个儿子叫丹 一年前失踪了
He has a son called Dan,who went missing a year ago.
全是泰文你看得懂吗
Can you read Thai?
这 这个是哪 一个华人超市
Where is this?- A Chinese market.
就在唐人街
It's in Chinatown.
那这个呢
And where is this?
幸运 咖啡馆
Lucky Coffee Shop.
剑指东方 走这边
It points to the east. This way.
去哪里呀 咖啡馆
Where are we going?- The coffee shop.
这跟咖啡馆有什么关系 我问你话呢
What does the coffee shop have to do with it? Answer me.
视频我都看过了
I watched all the footages.
在你之前 没有人只进未出过
Before you were there,everybody went in and out.
在你之后 也没人再进去
And after you left,nobody went in.
而且 那就只有一个入口
Besides,there is only one entrance.
所以呢就怀疑我是凶手 要么就是
So you think I'm the murderer?- Or...
谁 鬼
Who?- A ghost.
鬼和咖啡馆有什么关系啊
What does the ghost have to do with the coffee shop?
相机摆放的位置
According to the placement of the camera...
说明死者经常使用它
...the victim used it all the time.
但是里面就是没有SD卡
But there's no SD card in it.Unless...
除非 被人拿走啦
It was taken out.
可我还是不明白 这跟咖啡馆有什么关系
I still don't know what it has to do with the coffee shop.
死者这三个月来 常去的地方
For the past three months,the usual haunts of the victim...
除了超市 就是这
...are the supermarket and the coffee shop.
为什么要去这么远的地方喝咖啡
Why did he go all the way there to have coffee?
咖啡好喝
Because the coffee there is good.
最后一个线索 你去不去
This is the last clue.Are you coming or not?
凶手已经嚣张到 来警察局挑衅了
The murderer is so arrogant that he provoked in the police office!
你们这么多人都抓不到他
And you actually let him slip away!
我要发动全曼谷的警察抓捕这个唐仁
I will order all the cops of Bangkok to get Tang Ren.
三天 我给你们三天时间
Three days.I'll give you three days.
抓不住唐仁 你们都去NANA摸屁股吧
If you can't get him by then,you can sell yourselves at Nana!
见过这人没有
Have you seen this guy?
这个人啊 之前经常来的
This guy used to come here all the time.
坐在那个位置 最近不知道怎么了 就不来了
He sat there every time. But he hasn't shown up for a while.
还有什么特别的 没什么特别的
Anything special about him?- Nothing special.
他喜欢拿个破相机 对着外面 拍来拍去的
He often aimed his camera at the outside and took pictures.
你好 两位SIR 咖啡还是茶 必须要喝吗
Hello. Sirs, coffee or tea?- Do we have to drink something?
拜托 这是咖啡馆好吗 好 来杯咖啡啦
Come on, this is a coffee shop.- Fine, a coffee for me.
一百株 谢谢
100 baht.- Thank you.
就一破楼有什么好拍的
Why would anyone want to take pictures of a lousy building?
他拍的就是这个破楼
The building was his target.
我要查看这里的住户登记册
I want to check the household register here.
不行
No, you can't.
两位SIR 咖啡还是茶 我们刚才不是点过了吗
Sirs, coffee or tea?- I thought we ordered coffee.
但是你们又出去了呀 我们又回来啦
But you left.- But we come back now.
你们出去再回来也是要重新点的呀
You have to order again when you come back.
我们就上了个厕所啊
We just went to the bathroom.
第一 你们是一起去上的厕所
Firstly, you went to the bathroom at the same time.
第二 你们上的不是我们家的厕所
Secondly,you didn't use our bathroom.
第三 你们上厕所的时间未免也 太长了吧
Thirdly, it took you too long in the bathroom.
来杯咖啡啦 一百株
A coffee for me.-100 baht.
我要给你们点个差评啦 谢谢
I'll give a negative comment!- Thank you.
这是什么意思
What does this mean?
公 公帕 丁 沙丁
Gongpa Shading...
公泰普萨提萨散 一所中学的名字
Gong Tai Pu Sa Ti Sa San.The name of a middle school.
是颂帕失踪儿子的学校
Sompat's son studied there.
两份资料里 唯一重合的信息
This is the only overlapping information in the two materials.
算是突破口吗 最强大脑啊
Is it a breakthrough?You have an amazing mind.
人肉相机 还自带辨识功能
You are a human camera and an automatic recognition machine.
去看看谁在家
Let's see who they are.
谁呀 我们是警察
Who is it?- The police.
一会咋说 我自己来说啦
What should we say?- Leave it to me.
中国人 对啊 你也是啊
Are you Chinese?- Yes, so are you.
小妹妹 太巧了 看 我们是警察
What a coincidence.Look. We are with the police.
可不可以问你几句话啦 嗯
Can we ask you a few questions?
你叫什么名字啊 我叫思诺
What's your name?- I'm Snow.
大人不在 爸爸上工了
Your parents are not home?- My dad has gone to work.
你这么小也可以当警察啊
Aren't you too young to be a cop?
他是我的助手啦
He is my assistant.
小妹妹 这个人你认识吗 他是我隔壁班同学
Do you know him?- He is my schoolmate.
好久都没有去学校了
He has been absent from school for a long time.
大家都说他失踪了
Everybody says he has gone missing.
你知道是什么原因吗
Do you know why?
这个人认识吗
Do you know this guy?
那你有没有感觉 最近有人在跟踪你呀 没有啊
Are you stalked by anyone lately?- No.
那最近有没有什么怪事发生
Did anything weird happen to you lately?
或者你遇到什么怪人呢
Did you run into any weirdos?
你们 算吗
Do you guys count?
你干嘛
What are you doing?
你 真好看 谢谢
You are so pretty.- Thank you.
年轻气盛啊
Youth.
有没有发现什么
Have you got anything?
你是不是对人家小妞有意思啊
You have a crush on her,don't you?
你胡说什么呢你 一看你就对人家小妞有意思啦
What are you talking about?- It's so obvious.
又来
Again!
我们老板有请
Our boss wants to see you.
老板好啊
Nice to meet you.
知道你们偷的黄金 是谁的吗 闫先生的
Do you know who is the owner of the stolen gold? Mr. Yan.
闫先生 那黄金不是我们偷的啊
Mr. Yan, we didn't steal the gold.
闫先生 你的黄金不是我们偷的啊
警察说是你们
The police told me it was you.
警察也经常搞错啊
The police makes mistakes all the time.
我知道偷你黄金的五个人是谁了
I know the five guys who stole your gold.
谁 我说出来 你就把我们放啦
Who are they?- Let us go after I tell you.
跟我讨价还价 不 不 不
Are you bargaining with me?- No, no, no.
死的人是颂帕 黄兰登的助手托尼
The victim Sompat,Huang Landeng's assistant Tony...
一个东北人 还有一个越南人
...a northeasterner,a Vietnamese...
还有一个叫金刚的 胖吧拉唧的 傻大个子
...and a fat, big guy,called King Kong.
我怎么知道你说的是真的
How do I know if you are telling the truth?
他可以证明啊 我可以证明
He can prove it.- I can prove it.
你们这是在搞笑是不是
Are you kidding me?
我也可以证明
I can prove it, too.
阿香 闫先生
Xiang.- Mr. Yan.
那三个人我见过
I met those three guys.
而且我知道 是坤泰帮他们找了跑路的船
And I know that Kon Tai helped him get the boat to leave here.
如果黄金在他们手里 他们是不会回来的
If they have the gold,they wouldn't have stayed.
阿香 闭嘴
Xiang.- Shut up.
闫先生 请你相信阿香
Mr. Yan, please believe me.
就算不是你们偷的 但是黄金终归是你从颂帕那给运走的
Even if you didn't steal it, you moved it from Sompat's Workshop.
可我完全是不知情啊
I knew nothing about it.
看在阿香的面子上 我给你十天的时间找回黄金
For Xiang's sake, I'll give you ten days to find the gold.
十天之内 我保证不会难为你们
I won't touch you within ten days.
十天之后 会把你扔到湄南河去
Find it in time, or I will throw you into the Menam River...
喂鳄鱼
...to feed the crocodiles.
还不谢谢闫先生 十天
Thank Mr. Yan for that.- Ten days?
给二十天吧 七天
How about twenty days?- Seven days.
半个月 半个月好啦
Half a month.Half a month will do.
五天 行 行 好 五天就五天
Five days.- Fine, fine. Five days.
不能再减了 再减就成负的了
It can't be less than that.
你看行吗
What do you think?
好 OK 成交
Okay, it's a deal.
三天 就三天
Three days. Just three days.
你疯啦
Are you out of your mind?
好 就三天
All right, three days.
我们一言为定 你就害死我吧
I'll give you three days.- You are going to get me killed.
我给你三天的时间 五天我就赶不上回家飞机了
I don't have that much time before I go home.
有任何需要我帮忙 尽管开口
Just let me know if you need any help.
三天一过 我保证
Find the gold in time,or I promise that...
你会去见鳄鱼
...you will be fed to the crocodiles.
疯了 你一定是疯了
Crazy. You must be crazy.
五天不要 要三天
You asked for three days instead of five.
三天我们去哪里找黄金啊
How can we find the gold in three days?
你知道闫先生是谁吗
Do you know who Mr. Yan is?
唐人街金铺一大半都是他开的啦
Most of the gold shops in Chinatown are owned by him.
出租车 大市场 华人超市 KTV
The taxi company, floating market,Chinese market and KTV club...
那都是他开的啦
...are all owned by him.
全泰国黑白两道 都没人敢惹他
The officials or the gangsters,nobody wants to mess with him.
就连军方都得给他面子
Even the military shows him respect.
他说让我们喂鳄鱼 就会把我们喂鳄鱼啦
If he said we would be fed to the crocodiles, we would.
他说的是你 不是你们
He meant you, not us.
你什么意思 这时候分你我啦
What are you talking about?You want to be done with me now?
我们不是搭档吗 唐人街神探吗
Aren't we partners?The detectives of Chinatown?
我还是你舅舅呢 你有没有点人性
And I'm your uncle, too.You are inhumane!
现在去哪里啊 去那女孩学校看看
Where are we going now?- To the girl's school.
现在你还去泡妞
You are going to pick up girls now?
大哥 我们只有三天
We only have three days.
三天就喂鳄鱼了
Then we will be fed to the crocodiles.
只有把凶杀案破了 才能找回黄金
Only after we solve the murder can we find the gold.
你破个屁 你有一点点线索吗 这几天我一直都在陪你玩
Nonsense! Do you have any clues?I have been with you these days.
你有个毛线索啊
I don't think you have gotten anything.
凶手在哪里呢
Where is the murderer?
你连人家什么时候进去杀人 什么时候出来你都不知道
You don't even know when he went in and out.
你别以为你多看了几本侦探小说 就真把自己当神探了吗
You think you are a real detective because you read a few fictions?
谁陪谁玩啊 我是来放假的
You're wrong.I'm on vacation here.
结果呢 大皇宫呢
And? I haven't gone to the Grand Palace.
我这几天 我吃过饭 睡过觉吗
I haven't eaten or slept for the last few days.
反正还剩三天
Anyway, there are three days left.
我知道了 三天一到 你就打飞的回国了
I know. Three days later,you will fly home...
扔下我去喂鳄鱼 对不对
...and leave me here for the crocodiles, won't you?
对
Yes.
我们是搭档 唐人街神探
Partners,the detectives of Chinatown.
都是骗我的 对不对 对
They are all lies, aren't they?- Yes.
我可是你舅舅啊 表的
I am your uncle.- No, just a distant uncle.
我没你这么LOW的舅舅
I don't have a loser uncle like you.
你是小唐 我是老秦
You are Tang, and I'm Qin.
你别以为我离开你个小毛孩子 我就找不到黄金 破不了案
You think I can't find the gold and solve the case without you?
我还不当你这个保姆了呢
I don't want to be your babysitter anymore.
你以为我愿意陪你这个脑残啊
You think I want to be with a moron like you?
散伙 散伙就散伙 散伙
Break up!- Fine. Break up!
闫先生要见你
Mr. Yan wants to see you.
大叔呢 没和你一起来
Where is your uncle?He is not with you?
我 家里没人 走吧
I...- Nobody's home. Let's go.
借个火
Give me a light.
你怎么又是一个人在家
Why are you alone at home again?
我爸妈死于一场车祸
My parents died in a car accident.
养父从孤儿院里把我带回来
My stepfather adopted me from the orphanage.
他在上工
He has gone to work.
你呢 你父母呢
What about your parents?
我妈很早以前就去世了
My mother passed away a long time ago.
那你爸爸呢 在牢里
What about your dad?- He is in prison.
他犯了什么罪啊  我也不太清楚
What did he do?- I don't know.
那他是坏人吗
Is he a bad guy?
好 坏 看怎么理解了
Good or bad, it depends.
你说话一直这样吗
Do you always talk like this?
我之前就不太说话
I barely talked when I was younger.
现在好多了
I'm better now.
你们为什么要冒充警察
Why did you pose as police?
谁说的 你不是很上镜
Who told you that?- You are not so photogenic.
那你为什么还放我进来 我觉得 你不是坏人
So why did you invite me in?- I don't think you are a bad guy.
可是你们为什么要来找我 丹的爸爸 他一直在跟踪你
But why did you come to me?- Dan's father was stalking you.
是吗 为什么啊 我也想知道
Did he? Why?- I want to know that, too.
今天物理老师留了一个很奇怪的作业
Our physics teacher left us a funny assignment today.
如何把一张纸给立起来
To make a piece of paper stand.
这也太简单了 是太简单了
It can't be so simple.- Yes, you are right.
爸爸
Dad.
他是谁 同学
Who is he?- My classmate.
那我先走了
I have to go.
我送你
I'll see you out.
黄兰登 你别追了
Huang Landeng, stop chasing me.
你不跑 我就不追了
Only if you stop running.
你不追 我就不跑了
I will, as soon as you stop.
你不跑 我就不追了
Not before you stop.
你跑啊 跑死我了
Go ahead. I'm exhausted.
你别逼我 你要再逼我
Don't push me.If you push me again...
我就跳下去 你跳啊
...I'll jump.- Go ahead, jump!
天灵灵 地灵灵 天都帮不了你
God bless me.- Even God can't help you now.
唐仁 盗窃黄金 谋杀颂帕
Tang Ren, you stole the gold and murdered Sompat.
我要逮捕你
You are under arrest.
再见 唐仁 你给我回来
Hello.- Tang Ren, come back here!
我猜你就在这里啦
I knew you'd be here.
我知道了
I know.
你说 那些录像里 除了我没有其他人进出 对不对
The video footages showed that there was nobodygoing in or out but me, right?
对
Right.
你和警察确定 这里没有其它入口 对不对
You and the police are sure there's no other entrance, right?
对 颂帕 是被这降魔杵打死的
Yes.- Sompat was killed by the vajra.
他会不会 是他做了太多坏事
Is it possible that he did too many evils...
金刚显灵
...and the vajra made its power felt?
金刚来了
The vajra is here!
这么恐怖的事你还笑得出来
How can you laugh at such a creepy thing?
监视器内容 七天会自动覆盖
The footages are automatically overwritten every seven days.
所以呢
So?
我不相信什么鬼神
I don't believe in supernatural beings.
唯一的解释 凶手
The only explanation is that the murderer...
一周前就藏在这儿了
...had been hiding here a week before.
什么 一周前就藏在这儿啦 这怎么可能呢
What? Hiding here a week before?How is that possible?
歌野晶午的《求道者密室》
In Shogo Utano's "The Secret Chamber of the Seeker"...
凶手为了杀人 躲在天井里
...the murderer hid in the courtyard for a month...
一个月
...to kill someone.
大哥 那是小说嘛
That's fictional.
福尔摩斯说过
Sherlock Holmes said...
排除所有不可能
...when you have eliminated all which is impossible...
剩下那个多不可思议
...then whatever remains,however improbable...
都是事实真相
...must be the truth.
那他藏在哪里呢 不会被发现吗
So where did he hide?He'd be discovered, wouldn't he?
你还记得丹的房间吗
Do you remember Dan's room?
颂帕不会经常进自己死儿子的房间
Sompat didn't often go to the room of his dead son.
他就躲在丹的床底下
So the murderer hid under Dan's bed.
那个脚印 是他不小心留下的
He left that footprint by accident.
对 可他每天吃什么呢
Yes.- But what did he eat every day?
他的大小便怎么办呢
And what if he wanted to go the bathroom?
颂帕常去咖啡馆 你还记得吧
Sompat often went to the coffee shop, remember?
这个人啊 之前经常来这
This guy used to come here all the time.
自己家里 一直藏着一个 想杀死自己的人
A man who wants to kill you has been hiding in your home.
这想想太恐怖了
It's so creepy just to think of it.
现在我们案件重演
Now let's re-enact the murder.
有这个必要吗
Is it necessary?
要破解罪恶 就必须接近它 甚至成为它
To solve the crime, you have to approach it, or even be it.
我演你 你演颂帕
I'll play you,and you'll play Sompat.
老板 取货
Sir, I'm here for a pick up.
不对 怎么了
No.- What?
我说这话时没结巴 你演你
I didn't stutter.- Fine, you play yourself.
我演颂帕
I'll play Sompat.
记住 别错过任何 细节
Remember, don't miss any details.
取货
I'm here for a pick up.
坐
Sit.
停
Stop.
你的指纹 继续吗
Your finger prints.- Go on?
继续
Go on.
停 又停
Stop.- Again?
你确定 他是先给你钱 再给你单子的
Are you sure he paid you before he handed you the note?
对啊 怎么了 他自始至终只跟你说了一个坐
Yes. Why?- All he said to you was "sit"?
没错啊 好 继续
Yes.- Okay. Go on.
停 我就知道啦
Stop.- I knew it.
你走的时候 没看见颂帕
When you left,you didn't see Sompat?
他在工作室里 我只看到他的影子啦
He was in his studio,and all I saw was his silhouette.
影子
His silhouette.
你那天看到的 是不是这样的颂帕
The Sompat you saw that day was like this, wasn't he?
对 对 对 就是这个样子
Yes, exactly.
到底怎么回事 凶手在哪里呢
What's going on?Where is the murderer?
凶手就在你眼前 你是凶手
He is right beneath your eyes.- You are the murderer?
对 我是凶手 别闹了你
Yes, I am the murderer.- Stop it!
不是 我演的这个是凶手
No. The man I play is the murderer.
你演的是颂帕 颂帕杀死了自己
You play Sompat.You mean Sompat killed himself?
我知道了 他是自杀
I know. He committed suicide.
神探大哥 你自己砸碎自己后脑勺试试
Detective, try to smash the back of your own head.
到底怎么回事吗
So what the heck happened?
你没看清他的脸 对不对 对啊 那灯光太暗了嘛
You didn't see his face clearly.- The light was too dim.
那天是不是这个样子 对啊 就是这个样子啦
Was it like this that day?- Yes, exactly like this.
那是他不想让你看清
He didn't want you to see him clearly...
因为 他根本就不是颂帕
...because he was not Sompat.
难道他是 凶手
He was...- The murderer.
凶手来啦
The murderer is here!- Right.
你没事吧 我没事
Are you okay?- I'm fine.
他是谁呀 他要杀我们
Who is he?- He wants to kill us.
只能证明 证明什么
It means...- What?
我们对了 我们对了
We are right.- We are right?
不好 快跑啊
Oh, no!- Run!
小唐
Tang!
老秦 小唐
Qin!- Tang!
老秦
Qin!
小唐 小唐 我在这呢
Tang,Tang, I'm here!
老秦
Qin!
帮帮忙 帮帮忙 大哥 快点 快点啊
Come on, help us.Come on, come on.
不要命了吗
Do you want to live?
走 一 二 三
Let's go! One, two, three.
你要这个东西干什么
What do you want this for?
这是证据
This is evidence.
查案重要 还是活着重要啊
Which is more important,your life or solving the case?
都重要
They are both important.
走啦
Let's go.
闫先生已经知道我底细啦 泰国我是待不下去了
Mr. Yan has blown my cover.I can't stay in Thailand anymore.
你可以去澳洲啊 那边阳光好
You can go to Australia.There's great sunshine...
海鲜也很棒啊 是哦
...and delicious seafood.- Really?
对呀 你们耍我啊
Yes.- Are you kidding me?
很简单 我数三声
It's simple. I'll count to three.
告诉我黄金在哪里 不然我一枪打死她
And you tell me where the gold is.Or I'll shoot her.
一 我们真的不知道啊
One.- We really don't know.
你真的不知道吗 我真的不知道啊
Really?- I really don't know!
你真的不知道吗 真的不知道啊
Really?- Really!
大哥
My friend.
可怜可怜我吧 我真的很惨的
Have some pity on me.
我们几个人 策划了半年多
We spent over six months planning for this.
好不容易黄金到手了 现在什么都没了
And when we finally got the gold,it was gone.
现在泰国我 待不下去了
Now I can't stay in Thailand anymore.
我还有妈妈要照顾  我只能跑路
I still have to provide for my mother. I have to leave here.
很惨的
I am in misery.
把枪放下 你告诉他
Put the gun down.- You tell him.
我
Me?
我 哦 对 他本来就结巴
I...- Well, he is a stutterer.
这一紧张就更结巴啦
And even more so when he is nervous.
不着急 慢慢来 我等你 大把时间啊
Take it easy. I can wait.I have a lot of time.
二 别
Two.- Don't!
我 我知道了
I...- I know!
唱歌就不结巴 对 你把想说的都唱出来呀
You won't stutter if you sing.You can sing it out.
我不会唱 唱歌有什么难的
I can't sing.- What's so difficult about that?
我唱一句 你唱一句
Sing along with me.
时光一逝永不回
Time is gone with the wind.
预备 唱
Ready? Sing!
时光一逝 停 停 停
Time is gone...- Stop, stop, stop.
跑调了 不对 你唱得不对
You are out of tune.You're singing it wrong.
嗦啦嗦咪 啦咪啦哆啦哆
So la so mi. La mi la do la do.
时光一逝 啦咪啦哆啦哆
Time is gone...- La mi la do la do.
永不回 对 对 对 好很多了
With the wind.- It sounds better now.
你那个光唱得特别好 你再把那个回再拉得长一点
Your "time" sounds very well.You have to keep "wind" longer.
回 拉长一点儿啦
Wind. Keep it longer.
永不回 回
Gone with the wind.- Wind.
你们觉得我很二吗 我是不是很二 好啊 我二 OK 给你们最后一个机会
Do you think I'm dumb? Am I dumb?This is your last chance.
不要 二点八
No!- Two and a half.
你快告诉他 别吵 我 我 我
Just tell him!- I...
你这个小结巴 说 关键时刻你就结巴 怪不得你考不上大学
You are such a loser. No wonder you can't get into college.
大学就不能要你这个小结巴
No college will admit a little stutterer like you.
那也比你好 你还侦探呢
I'm better than you.You think you are a detective.
你就是个老流氓 你敢骂我
You are actually an old hooligan.- How dare you call me that?
我骂你怎么了 老流氓
So what? You old hooligan!- You little stutterer!
你个小结巴 你个老流氓
You old hooligan!- You little stutterer!
You old hooligan!- I'm the point.
你个老结巴 重点是我 小流氓
You old stutterer!- Little hooligan!
阿香 你没事吧 我没事
Xiang, are you okay?- I'm okay.
阿香 阿香
Xiang!Xiang!
滴滴打车 送医院啊
Use DiDi Taxi to take her to the hospital.
还萨瓦迪卡呢 叫救护车
What are you talking about?Call the ambulance!
阿香
Xiang!
请您止步
Please stop here.
走啊 往哪走啊
Let's go!- Where to?
警察 来就来
The police is here!- I don't care!
大不了被抓走啊
They can arrest me here.
阿香 原来这么爱我
Xiang, now I know how much you love me.
肯为我挡枪
You are willing to take a bullet for me.
我怎么能辜负她呢 你想多了吧
How can I let her down?- You think too much.
等她好了 我要跟她生孩子 生很多很多孩子
When she gets well, I'll have kids with her. A lot of kids.
很多很多孩子
A lot of kids.
看我干什么
Why are you looking at me?
谢谢你救了我
Thanks for saving me.
别怪我拖累你就好啦 好好的假期
I hope you don't blame me for dragging you down.
怎么变成这个样子
Your vacation turns out like this.
你为什么来泰国
Why did you come to Thailand?
有哪个人 在国内混得舒坦 愿意出来呢
Anyone who has a good life at home won't go to another country.
留下有留下的原因 出来有出来的理由啦
We all have reasons to go abroad and stay.
误会了
It's not like that.
大哥
Eldest brother.
误会了
It's not like that.
很快整个镇子 都知道了这件丑事
In no time, the whole town knew about the scandal.
那时候 我才明白 你打算用什么料补呢
I finally realise that...- What would you like me to use?
这世上 比所有人瞧不起你还难受的滋味
Being pitied by everyone is more miserable than...
就是让所有人同情你
...being despised by them.
这么久了 你不想回去吗
It's been a long time.Don't you want to go home?
外面千好万好 都不如家好
There is no place like home.
可是回去又能干什么呢
But what can I do,even if I go back?
牛皮都已经吹出去了
I have been bragging aboutmy life here.
人家都以为你在外面混得风生水起
They all think I have a successful career.
其实 牙掉了 咽肚里
But I have to bear my own cross.
苦只有自己知道
And nobody knows my bitterness.
那些在外面 漂着不回家的人 都有自己的难处
Anybody who stay away from home have their own problems.
你呢 这么聪明
What about you? You are so smart.
警校不要你 那可是他们很大的损失呀
It's the police college's loss for rejecting you.
秦风同学 你为什么要报考刑警学院
Qin Feng, why do you want to get into the Criminal Police College?
这个问题很难回答吗
Is it so hard to answer?
我 不想说假话 我们也不想听假话呀
I don't want to lie to you.- We don't want you to lie.
我想完成一次 完美的犯罪
I want to commit a perfect crime.
啊 你是这么说
What? You actually said that?
你还真是个怪胎
You are really a freak.
看了这么多书和电影
You read all the books and watch all the movies...
不为破案 为犯罪
...not to solve crimes,but to commit one?
和你那 一直在狱里的老爸有关系
Does it have something to do with your dad in prison?
下回告诉你 下回 哪个下回
I'll tell you next time.- Next time? When is that?
没有生命危险
She's out of danger.
没事啦
She is fine.
这下跑不掉啦
We can't run away this time.
案子不是推理得差不多了吗 要不我们投降吧
The case is almost solved.How about we surrender?
不行 还差一点儿
No, I need the last piece of the puzzle.
还跑 跑
We have to run again?- Yes.
这回真跑不了啦 外面那么多警察 怎么跑啊
With all the police out there,we really can't escape this time.
有了 找救兵
Got it! Let's get help.
哥 有消息了
Brother, any news?
托尼说人和货 都在医院
Tony says Tang Ren and the gold are all in the hospital.
哥 咱的苦日子到头了
Brother, our ordeal is coming to an end.
算他妈到头啦
Finally!
走啊 进 进
Come on! Hurry up!
死不瞑目啊
You didn't die in peace.
安静
Quiet.
安静 安静 安静
Quiet, quiet, quiet.
站住
Stop!
是的 市长您放心 绝不会再有这样的事了
It will never happen again.Yes, Mayor.
你们听到了
You all heard that.
这次行动也不是完全没有收获啊
We have actually accomplished something in this operation.
盗窃团伙也被我们击毙了一个人 抓获了两个人啊
We shot a man dead and arrested two of the robbers.
所以 你们就炸毁了一个医院
So you blew off a hospital?
上次是警察局 这次是医院
After the police station,and now it's the hospital.
抓一个唐仁 你们是不是要毁掉整个曼谷
Do you have to blast the whole Bangkok to get Tang Ren?
不是不是 我不听你们废话了
No.- I don't want to hear that.
不是 明天是最后期限
No.- Tomorrow is the deadline.
你们再抓不到唐仁 就一起滚到COWBOY摸屁股
If you can't get him by then,you can sell yourselves at Cowboy!
不是NANA吗 滚
I thought you said Nana.- Get out!
你知道谁是凶手啦 思诺养父 李
Do you know who the murderer is?- Snow's stepfather, Lee.
啊 怎么会是他呢 他在废车厂工作
How can it be him?- He works at the junk yard.
巧是巧 可你也不能说
It's a coincidence.But it doesn't mean...
他就是凶手啊
...he is the murderer.
四月十三号以前 他请了一周的假
He took a week's leave before April 13th.
不巧了吧 你怎么知道
Not so much a coincidence, huh?- How do you know that?
我问了废车厂的华裔经理
I asked the Chinese guy at the junk yard.
可是黄金呢 我们还剩下两天
But what about the gold?We have two days left.
我可不想不坐牢就去喂鳄鱼啊
I don't want to go to prison or be fed to the crocodiles.
这一切都是他精心策划好的
This is all elaborately planned by him.
我们找到凶手 就找到黄金了
We will find the gold when the murderer is found.
那我们现在去哪里啊
So where are we going now?
去找杀人动机
To find out the motive for murder.
思诺
Snow.
安眠药 自杀
Sleeping pills. Suicide.
干什么 人工呼吸啊
What are you doing?- Give her mouth-to-mouth.
呼个毛线啊 又不是溺水
Cut it out.It's not like she is drowned.
对 对 赶快送医院啦
Right, let's take her to hospital.
上面写的什么 杀人动机
What's in there?- The motive.
什么杀人动机
What motive?
到底写的什么
What's really in there?
怎么样
How is she?
已经给她洗胃了 没危险的
We have pumped her stomach.She is out of danger now.
没事啦
She is fine.
阴魂不散啊
They just won't leave us alone.
小唐 我知道了
Tang, I get it now.
知道什么了 先找辆车
What?- Let's find a car.
干什么 去颂帕工坊
What for?- Go to Sompat's Workshop.
现在 最后再赌一把
Now?- This is our last chance.
赌什么 黄金
For what?- To find the gold.
黄SIR 唐仁
Sir, it's Tang Ren.
在那呢 追 追 追 快 快
Over there.- Get him, go, go, go!
在前面堵住他们啊
Block them at the next intersection.
看那里啊 大皇宫啊
Look there! It's the Grand Palace.
没有我命令不准开枪
Don't shoot. I want him alive.
唐仁 放弃抵抗 赶紧投降
Tang Ren, give up resistance and surrender now.
怎么办 看你往哪跑
What do we do now?- You have nowhere to go now.
冲过去呀
Run them over!
快跑呀
Run!
抓活的 抓活的
Get him alive!
这里啦
Here!
上车追呀
Get in the car and go after them!
让一让 让一让
Excuse me! Excuse me!
这样我们到不了唐人街
We can't get to Chinatown this way.
快给闫先生打电话啦
Call Mr. Yan.
谢谢你们把托尼交给我
Thank you for giving Tony to me.
但你们还剩不到两天
But you only have less than two days.
不用两天 今天就可以把黄金给你
We don't need two days.We can get your gold back today.
但是 你要帮我们
But you have to help us!
快 快
Go, go!
走开 走开
Get out of the way!
绕过去 绕过去
Go around them!
天助我也啦
Help from heaven.
走 走 走
Let's go!
自寻死路 给我包围这里
Digging your own grave.Besiege here!
你到底在找什么 黄金啊
What are you looking for?- The gold.
不是被我运出去了吗 应该还在这
I moved it.- It should still be here.
一百公斤东西 不难找
It weighs over 100kg.Shouldn't be so hard to find it.
警察前面找了好多次啦 都没有找到啊
The police searched several times,but couldn't find anything.
快点找
Find it!
找不到呢 找不到就死定啦
What if we can't find it?- We will be dead meat.
大声公
The megaphone!
里面的人听着
The men in there,listen carefully.
不要再抵抗了 你们已经被包围了
Don't kick against the pricks.You are besieged.
唐仁 我的忍耐是有限度的 现在我数三个数
Tang Ren, I only have so much patience. I'll count to three.
如果你再不出来 我就要进去了
If you don't come out by then,we will go in.
我们就要进去啦
We will go in.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
唐仁 你脑子是不是有问题
Tang Ren, what's wrong with you?
拿佛像来当人质呀
Are you holding the Buddha statue hostage?
黄兰登 你要的黄金在这里呀
Huang Landeng, the gold you are looking for is in here.
什么鬼啊
What the heck?
黄金一直在这里
The gold is in here the whole time.
根本就没有出去过
It never left the place.
只不过 颂帕把它给铸成佛型了
Sompat made it into a Buddha statue...
还没来得及告诉他同伙 就被杀死啦
...but he got killed before he could tell his partners.
五人 盗金团伙
The five suspects of the robbery gang...
分别是颂帕 还有你的助手托尼
...are Sompat,your assistant Tony...
昨晚在医院见得那三个人
...and the three guys at the hospital yesterday.
黄金失主 闫先生可以证明啊
The owner of the stolen gold,Mr. Yan, can prove that.
可是颂帕还是你杀的 不是我
But you are still the murderer.- No, I'm not.
凶手另有其人 我们已经找到他了
It's someone else.- We have found him.
可以马上带你去找他 当面指证
And we can take you to him now.- To testify against him.
黄兰登 我知道你是铁血神探
Huang Landeng,I know you are the Hot Fuzz.
难道你不想知道事情的真相吗 很刺激的
Don't you want to know the truth?- It's thrilling.
我再相信你一次 别跟我耍花样啊
I'll believe you one more time.Don't play tricks with me.
黄金案归你了 不是我
The gold robbery case is yours.- What?
凶杀案当然是我的啦 我
And the homicide case is mine.- I...
副局长当然也是我啦
And I will be the deputy chief, too.
喝喝这个补补脑
Here, it's brain-boosting.
你还有什么不明白的吗 一会儿 你和凶手对质
Do you have any questions?You confront the murderer.
为什么又是我 不是你呀
Why me again?
你 你说呢
What do you think?
你不该这么做的
You shouldn't have done this.
你好啊 雇主先生 你什么意思
Nice to meet you.- What are you talking about?
我们见过 就在颂帕死的那天晚上 你忘记啦
We met on the night Sompat was killed. Don't you remember that?
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you are talking about.
这话好像是 烂俗电影里大反派的回答
It sounds like a line of the villain in a lame film.
女士们 先生们 我想说的是
Ladies and gentlemen,I would like to point out that...
颂帕被杀案 和黄金失窃案 这本来就是两个案子
...the murder of Sompat and the robbery are two different cases.
只不过恰巧的是 颂帕也是黄金盗匪之一
But coincidentally,Sompat was one of the robbers.
所以这个案子 才给我和黄警探带来了这么多的麻烦
So it brought so much trouble to Detective Huang and me.
说重点 故事 要从死者死前一周
Get to the point!- The story began from April 7th...
也就是说四月七日那天开始讲起
...which is seven days before the murder.
那天 我接到了一个陌生人的电话
On that day, I got a phone call from a stranger.
你好
Hello.
现在我知道了 打电话的人就是这位李先生
Now I know that the caller is Mr. Lee here.
这是他 计划的一小部分 先找一个合适的替死鬼
It's a part of his plan.Find a fall guy first.
我按约定到了颂帕工坊
I went to Sompat's Workshop as asked.
我以为见到的是死者颂帕
I thought the guy I met was Sompat.
而我见到的 却是这位李先生
But the man I really saw was Mr. Lee.
不可能 他怎么进入现场的
It's impossible.How did he get into the workshop?
监视器根本没有拍到他
He didn't even show up in the footages.
我们这位李先生 知道监视器内容
Mr. Lee knew that the video footages...
七天就会自动覆盖
...would be automatically overwritten every seven days.
所以他提前一周 就藏在了颂帕的家里
So he hid in Sompat's workshop a week in advance.
他在床下留下的脚印 暴露了他的踪迹
The footprint he had left under the bed gave him away.
四月十四日晚 我们的李先生算好了时间
On the night of April 14th,with careful timing...
在我要来之前 他用降魔杵杀死了颂帕
...Mr. Lee killed Sompat with the vajra before I showed up.
李先生那晚并没有开灯
Mr. Lee didn't turn on the light that night.
而点的却是蜡烛 这样便于迷惑我
He lit a candle instead because it could not only dazzle me...
更能让蜡烛自己燃尽
...but also burn out itself.
而他 早就换上了和颂帕一样的服装 头套 眼镜
And he dressed like Sompat,and put on wig and glasses...
就是为了让我以为 他就是颂帕
...to make me believe that he was Sompat.
很快 我就如约而至了
Soon, I arrived in time.
取货
I'm here for a pick up.
最最精彩的就要来了
Now is the highlight of the story.
我们一直百思不得其解
What we couldn't figure out was...
凶手是如何离开现场的呢
...how the killer left the crime scene.
就在刚刚 我撞翻了医院的手推车
Just a while ago, when I knocked over a trolley in the hospital...
我才想到了答案
...I figured it out.
这招简直就是太完美了
This is so perfect.
他要让我送的货 根本就是他自己
What he asked me to pick up was himself.
他钻进木箱后 打开了工作室的音响
He got into the box and turned on the speaker in the studio...
让我误以为 继续工作的是颂帕
...to make me believe that the working man was Sompat.
其实 我看到的不过是具尸体
But in fact,what I saw was a dead body.
他从里面锁住了箱子
He locked the box from inside.
我以为我运出去的是佛像
I thought I left with a Buddha statue.
你们以为我运出去的是黄金
And you thought I left with the gold.
谁都没想到 我运出去的却是他 杀人凶手
But no one ever thought that I left with him, the murderer.
杰克・福翠尔《遗失的镭》中
In Jacques Futrelle's "The Problem of the Lost Radium"...
凶手就是藏在皮箱里潜入研究所的
...the murderer snuck into the lab lying in a suitcase.
青崎有吾 写的《体育馆杀人》
In Yugo Aosaki's "Murder in the Gym"...
凶手也是躲在 一辆手推车里离开现场的
...the murderer left the scene in a trolley.
这种桥段 在我们侦探推理界里 并不新鲜
It's not something new in our detective world.
而我们这位凶手 利用监控录像
The murderer took advantage of the surveillance footages...
把我包装成了嫌疑犯
...to set me up,and took advantage of me...
利用嫌疑犯把真凶带出了现场
...to bring the real murderer out.
我不得不说 干得实在是太漂亮了
I have to say,he did such a good job.
要不是他 千算万算只算错了一步 替死鬼找到了
If he didn't miss a step and took the Number One detective...
唐人街第一神探 我的身上
...of Chinatown as his fall guy...
这个案子 简直就是 天衣无缝
...the crime he committed would have been perfect.
听着是精彩 但李先生的杀人动机在哪呢
It sounds interesting.But what's his motive?
你一定知道 颂帕的儿子 丹 一年前离奇失踪了
You must know that Sompat's son,Dan went missing a year ago.
知道啊 可是丹就是这位
Yes.- But what you don't know is...
思诺小姑娘的同学 你一定就不知道了
...that Dan is Snow's schoolmate.
It led us to another sad story.
You must have read this journal.- Whose journal is it?
Hers. She tried to burn it...
...before she attempted suicide,but we stopped her in time.
What's in the journal?- The motive for murder.
Snow's journal keeps track of...
...Sompat's psychological changes after his son had gone missing.
He started to stalk his son's schoolmates.
It's so creepy.- What's creepier is that...
...he brought Snow home and raped her.
Shut up!
The girl felt ashamed to tell anybody...
...so she kept the painful experience in her journal.
But unfortunately, her stepfather read the journal one day.
Even if what's in the journal is true...
...you can't testify against me.
I have never gone to that workshop or met Sompat.
That van comes from the junk yard.
And you work there, don't you?- It's just a coincidence.
Where is the evidence?
We fought against the real murderer last night.
If I've got it right,your right arm is injured.
Even if I am, it's from an accident at work a few days ago.
Look at you. Your eyebrows are pointy at the front...
...and wide at rear. You have a black mole at your Life Palace.
You have bloodshot eyes and crow's feet.
Someone having a face like that is either violent or wicked.
You want evidence, don't you?
The Bluetooth-enabled speaker can remember the users.
Turn on your phone and see if it connects automatically.
Dad, is this true?
I don't regret this.
I love you.
I know.- No, you don't know. I love you.
He has retrieved the stolen gold...
...and killed the murderer who tried to escape.
Let's welcome our new deputy chief of Chinatown Police, Kon Tai.
I hope you will come to Thailand again.
Thank you.- You must come for our wedding.
Who says I will marry you,pauper?
I have to call you aunt now?- Of course.
Aunt? Isn't he your cousin?Aren't you born in the 90s?
Goodbye!- Liars!
What? You don't want to leave?
What will you miss more,Thailand or the Thai people?
What are you talking about?- You don't want to leave me.
Stop, stop!
What is written on that signboard?
It's the name of that bar.
It's the most famous gay bar in Bangkok.
Sompat got divorced with his wife nine years ago.
The room is neither messy nor smelly.
He must be a sissy or a gay.
I thought you were going home today.
I want to tell you a story.
Both you and that uncle love stories.
A boy went missing. His father had been looking for him.
He suspected that his son was dead.
More importantly, he suspected the murderer of his son...
...might be a girl.
The girl found out about it.
She was afraid that she'd be exposed.
So she decided to get rid of the father.
She knew about the perverted love her stepfather had for her.
So she fabricated a journal...
...and let her stepfather read it intentionally.
I wondered what was in the part that was ripped off.
What was it that she didn't want us to know?
Maybe it was the way the murder was committed.
If I could kill him,I'd find a scrapped van...
...and a fall guy first.
I'd get into his house...
...before the footages are automatically overwritten.
I'd make him suffer thousands of times worse than I did.
The girl didn't expect that we'd come to her.
So she changed her plan and used us...
...to get rid of her perverted stepfather.
The timing the journal showed up and its burning speed...
...were exactly on spot.
But the girl didn't know that...
...the man she framed a rape against is a gay.
You don't stutter now.
Of course,these are all hypothesized.
No evidence can prove the sexual orientation of a dead man.
But I don't get it.- Forget it.
This book says,while we are individual lives...
...the summation of good and evil is invariant.
Everyone plays his role from birth.
Some of them are good,and some of them are evil.
What are you?
Should the villain smile like this?
So this is it?
There's nothing else I can do.- Nobody cares about the truth.
They only believe the truth they want to see.
Good and evil are incompatible.
When there is evil,there has to be good.
Yes. There are so many mysteries.
As detectives of Chinatown,we have to uphold justice...
...punish the evil and praise the good.
The plane!
What should I do?- How would I know?
So I have to endorse the ticket.
Or you can stay for another seven days.
I'll take you to the Grand Palace tomorrow.
No!